Michael Edward Gentilini (214) 477-0960

michael@dfwqualityappraisal.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dallasappraiser/

https://github.com/dallasappraiser

I am Michael Gentilini and I am transitioning to web development. I whistle while I work, am self driven, adaptable, and dedicated to finding solutions to the problems others shy away from. My prior experience as a business owner, as well as education in Linux/Unix and full stack development give me a unique perspective and abilities.

EDUCATION:

SMU, Dallas, Texas 03-2019 - Current

- 6 month intense Full Stack Bootcamp
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Bootstrap, Firebase, Git, Command Line (Bash)
- Still to learn: Express.js, React.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL and much more ...

Baker College, Flint, Michigan 09/2007 - 06/2009

- Associate of Applied Science, Linux/UNIX Systems Technology with Elective classes in Microsoft
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist –Windows Vista Configuration
- GPA 3.99

Carleton University, Ottawa, Canada 09/1995-05/1996

• International Business - classes in economics, mathematics, accounting, marketing, Russian

EXPERIENCE:

DFW Quality Appraisal LLC, Owner Certified Residential Appraiser 10/2016 - Current

- Owner and Chief Appraiser in the Dallas market.
- Public speaking to real estate professionals.

RWilliam Real Estate, Real Estate Appraiser 11/2015 - 10/2016

• Completed approximately 300 residential appraisals working with a small Dallas firm with the majority of the assignments in Dallas County.

Metrowest Appraisal Co. LLC, Staff Appraiser 03/2015 – 10/2015

Completed approximately 200 residential appraisals in Dallas and Collin Counties.

Compugain/Fannie Mae, NUC Review Appraiser (Contractor) 06/2013 -12/2014

• Conducted retrospective and current valuation desk reviews of national appraisal reports to support lending decisions and determine if they meet Fannie Mae guidelines, USPAP and other standards.

Appraisal Nation (AMC), Client/Vendor Relationship Specialist - Quality Control 01/2013 - 05/2013

• Performed qualitative residential appraisal reviews nationally.

Metrowest Appraisal Co. LLC, Staff Appraiser 10/2009 - 02/2013

• Completed approximately 700 appraisals in Michigan and North Carolina.

Redfern, Lucia & Associates, Real Estate Appraiser 05/2005 - 10/2009

• Inspected/Reviewed over 500 appraisals working directly with the Chief Review Appraiser.